travelmuse.com 2009-08-04

# TravelMuse: Privacy Policy - TravelMuse

_January 18, 2008_

Your privacy, and the privacy of all registered users of TravelMuse.com, is important to us. Accordingly, we have adopted the following privacy policy. Our policy is based on the principles of notice, choice, access and security in the collection and use of all information regarding our users and their activities at our site.

#### 1\. Notice

This policy tells you, among other things, what information we gather from you, how we may use or disclose that information and our efforts to protect it. Please read this policy carefully, and feel free to contact us at [Support@TravelMuse.com](mailto:support@travelmuse.com) if you have any questions regarding its contents.

_Types of Information Collected_

In connection with your use of our site, we ask for and may collect a variety of information from and about you in different ways. For example, when you register to use our site, we ask for and store your and/or your name, address, email address and other identifying contact data. In addition, we collect information relating to your travel plans, itineraries, trip planning, experiences or views regarding hotels, destinations, tours, places, or other travel-related information. We may also collect the information you disclose in any of our chat rooms, discussion groups and bulletin boards. In addition, we automatically receive and record information in our server logs from your browser, including your IP address, browser type, and the pages you request. This information does not necessarily enable us to personally identify you.

_Use of Cookies_

Use of our site requires that you accept the use of cookies, which are small data files that our Web site sends to your browser for storage on your computer’s hard drive. We use cookies to protect confidential data, track activity at our site and better serve your needs and interests.

_Use of Information_

We use your personally identifying information to identify and/or register you as a user of the site and (1) to verify your authorization to access certain features of the site, (2) to fulfill your requests for products or services and otherwise process transactions on the site, (3) to personalize and customize the content and relevant trip services that you are offered to contact you, (4) to improve our services, and (5) to provide reporting.

We may use your email address to contact you directly regarding services or products that we believe may be of interest to you. We may also associate your personally identifying information with information we collect about your preferences and activities at the site, such as the particular pages you request at the site and purchases or other transactions you effect through the site. We may vary the content you receive in future visits to the site based on your preferences and activities. We may combine your personally identifying information, and information about your preferences and activities, with those of all or a particular group of our users to prepare collective profiles of our users and their activities. For example, we may track the number of our users who view certain pages or use certain features or compile the total dollar amount of sales conducted through our site in a particular geographic region. Such information, and other information we derive from individual users’ information, allows us to continue to grow and provide you with quality fellow users through more accurate marketing and advertising of our web site.

_Disclosure of Information_

We may provide your personally identifying information, and information about your activities and preferences, to other companies wishing to contact you about products or services, but only to those that we believe impose reasonable safeguards on the privacy of your information. We may also provide these companies with collective profiles of our user groups and their activities and preferences. Such collective profiles may also be disclosed in describing our site and services to prospective partners, advertisers and other third parties, and for other lawful purposes. Finally, we may disclose information to fulfill certain legal and regulatory requirements or if we believe, in good faith, that such disclosure is legally required or necessary to protect others’ rights or to prevent harm. We may also transfer information about you if TravelMuse, Inc. is acquired by or merged with another company. In this event, TravelMuse, Inc. will notify you by sending a notice to the email address specified in your TravelMuse, Inc. account before information about you becomes subject to a different privacy policy.

_Links to Third Party Sites_

For your convenience, we may provide links to third party web sites or referrals to certain third parties’ products or services. If you choose to visit a third party’s web site or use its products or services, please be aware that this privacy policy will not govern your activities and any information you disclose to such third party.

#### 2\. Choice 

_Public vs. Private Trips_

Once you save your trip in TravelMuse, Inc.’s system, other users will be able to view your shared travel itinerary, unless you choose specifically not to share your travel plans (Private vs. Public trip). To ensure your privacy, TravelMuse, Inc. does not display your email address or contact information to users, unless you desire to do so. Please note that you if you choose to include personally identifiable information in your comments, open text fields, or other areas of the web site intended for public viewing, other users will be able to view and use this information. We recommend against posting your email address and other personally identifiable information in this manner unless you are comfortable with the possibility of receiving unsolicited contact.

_Deactivation or Changes_

We will offer you the ability to access, review and change certain information via the Registration page. Upon your request, we will deactivate your account, and remove your personal information from active service. To make this request, please contact us. Your account will be deactivated as soon as reasonably possible based on your account activity. We will retain in our files and databases some personal information to prevent fraud, collect any fees owed, resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, assist with any investigations, enforce our Terms of Service and comply with legal requirements as permitted by law. Therefore, you should not expect that all of your personal information will be completely removed from our databases in response to your request.

_Unsolicited Messages_

In addition, we will not send unsolicited messages to users of our site who indicate that they do not wish to receive such messages. If you do not wish to receive unsolicited email messages from us, please contact us at [Support@TravelMuse.com](mailto:support@travelmuse.com).

#### 3\. Access

At any time after you have logged on to our site, you may contact us at [Support@TravelMuse.com](mailto:support@travelmuse.com) to request access to information we have collected regarding you or your business or to notify us of changes to such information. If you request any such changes, we will contact you by email or fax to confirm those changes. Once confirmed, any new item of information will replace the corresponding information previously provided.

#### 4\. Security

We use industry-standard encryption methods to transmit your personal registration information from your computer to ours across the Internet, and we restrict access to any transactional portions of our site to computers running web browsers that support **Secure Socket Layer (“SSL”)** protocol. To use this protection technology, you need to have **an SSL-capable browser** , such as **Netscape Navigator 4.5 or higher, Microsoft Internet Explorer 4.5 or higher**. These browsers will automatically activate the technology when you log on to our site. Please remember that you play a valuable part in security as well. Your password to access our site, which you select at registration, should never be shared with anyone and should be changed frequently. And, after you have finished using our site, you should log off and exit your browser so no unauthorized persons can use our site with your name and account information. Remember that any information you voluntarily disclose on-line in any news or message postings, discussion groups or chat rooms may be collected and used by others without your permission. Furthermore, if you provide any information to parties who operate Web sites that are linked to or from our site, different rules may apply to their collection, use or disclosure of your personal information. We encourage you to review these sites’ policies before revealing any sensitive or personal information.

Regardless of the precautions taken by you or by us, “perfect security” does not exist on the Internet. We cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us, and you transmit such information at your own risk.

##### Changes to Privacy Policy

It may be necessary from time to time for us to modify this policy to reflect changes in the way we collect and use information or changes in privacy-related laws, regulations, and industry standards. Accordingly, we reserve the right to change this policy at any time by posting the revised policy on this web site. This policy was posted on January 18, 2008. Data will be handled in accordance with the policy in effect at the time the data is collected.
